Guide to the A.I.R. Gallery Archives MSS.184
Fales Library and Special Collections
- Series VI: Video recordings
  This series contains videorecordings pertaining to exhibitions and/or individual artists.
  - A.I.R. Gallery 1972 Opening and Discussion, September 16, 1972; ID: 184.0031 (Box 29, Vhs ID: 184.0031, Box Shared Fales 145, Dvd 184.0034)
    Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements
    Duration: 31 minutes
  - Angie Eng Demo; Image Bank, undated; ID: 184.0035 (Box 29, Media ID: 184.0035)
    Original format: Format: VHS; Fuji T-10
    Removed from Box 7, Folder 246
  - McKnight Fellowship Artists 32 minutes; Gilmor 1st 6 min., 1996-1997; ID: 184.0036 (Box 29, Media ID: 184.0036)
    Duration: 32 minutes
    Original format: VHS; 3M T-60
    Removed from Box 7, Folder 251
  - Lineage: Carolyn Martin 1995, 1988; ID: 184.0037 (Box 29, Media ID: 184.0037)
    Original format: VHS; T-15
    Removed from Box 8, Folder 284
  - Sheila Ross Environmental Installations Environment, Photography and Spoken Text by Sheila Ross Music by Mary Jane Leach, 2006; ID: 184.0038 (Box 29, Media ID: 184.0038)
    Duration: 14 minutes
    Original format: VHS; Fuji HQ T-120
    Removed from Box 9, Folder 302
  - A.I.R Roundtable, ID: 184.0026 (Box 29, Media ID: 184.0026)
    Original format: Hi-8mm; Fuji MP
  - Subseries A: Submasters - CLOSED
    CLOSED
    - 1972 Exhibition Opening and Discussion, undated (Box Shared Fales PM 7, Case 184.0033)
      Source ID
      184.0031
  - Subseries B: Preservation Masters - CLOSED
    - ID: 184.0032 (Box Shared Fales PM 51)
- Series VII: Dissertation
  This one-item series contains Dr. Bette J. Kauffman's doctoral dissertation, "'Women Artist': Constructing Social Identity," of which interviews with A.I.R. Gallery members constitutes a significant part.
  - Dr. Bette J. Kauffman, "'Woman Artist': Constructing Social Identity" (University of Pennsylvania Department of Philosophy, 1992) (Box 26, Folder 978)
- Series VIII: Archived Websites, May 2020-ongoing; 6 websites in 6 archived websites.
  This series contains the archived website for the A.I.R. Gallery. The website includes a history of the organization and Legacy Project, past and current exhibitions details dating back to 1994, exhibition press releases, artist biographies, fellowship programs, education program, research and development iniative, and events and programs. The gallery's website also contains resources in response to current events, such as abortion rights, Black Lives Matter, and the COVID-19 pandemic.
  The series also includes the website for the Scalability Project: Cacophony of Troubled Stories, an online exhibition and publication that included artworks, texts, and interviews with and by adrienne maree brown, Anna L. Tsing, biarritzzz, Daria Dorosh, Felice Grodin, Gordon Hall, Melanie Hoff, Klau Kinky, Naama Tsabar, Nahee Kim, Rebecca Jordan Young, and Tabita Rezaire. The exhibition was assembled due to the COVID-19 pandemic.
  In 2022, A.I.R. Gallery celebrated its 50th anniversary and published a digital exhibit detailing the history of the A.I.R. Gallery. The exhibit was made in collaboration with the Feminist Institute.
  Accruals
  https://www.airgallery.org/ is accrued semiannually.
  Due to technical or privacy issues, archived websites may not be exact copies of the original website at the time of the web crawl. Certain file types will not be captured dependent on how they are embedded in the site. Other parts of websites that the crawler has difficulty capturing includes Javascript, streaming content, database-driven content, and highly interactive content. Full-Text searches of archived websites are available at https://archive-it.org/organizations/567.
  Appraisal
  In the Google Arts & Culture exhibits, images are not successfully captured.
- OVERSIZE Series I: Administrative records
  - Subseries B: Gallery Administration
    - Website Layout, 2006 (Box 27, Folder 66)
  - Subseries D: Membership (Members/affiliates/job descriptions)
    - A.I.R. Members Portfolio, 1992 (Box 27, Folder 93A.)
  - Subseries G: Press/writings
    - 15th Anniversary Show: Essays by Lucy Lippard, 1987 (Box 27, Folder 192A.)
  - Subseries E: Programming
    - Film and video series, 1982-1983 (Box 27, Folder 135)
- OVERSIZE Series II: Individual artists
  - Riese, Beatrice, n.d. (Box 27, Folder 299A.)
  - Schneider, Kathleen, n.d. (Box 27, Folder 306A.)
  - Sperry, Ann, n.d. (Box 27, Folder 317)
- OVERSIZE Series III: Exhibition files
  - Subseries A: Exhibitions held at A.I.R.
    - "Atlanta Women's Art Collective at A.I.R.", Jan. 8-26, 1980 (Box 27, Folder 430)
    - "Women Choose Men: An Invitational Show of Works by Men", Sep. 28-Oct. 16, 1982 (Box 27, Folder 460)
    - Nancy Spero/Dale Emmart/Claire Lieberman, Apr. 5-23, 1983 (Box 27, Folder 469)
    - "Detail: The Special Task: An Exhibition of Works by Women Architects", June 5-23, 1984 (Box 27, Folder 485A.)
    - Sue Hettmansperger/National Affiliates, Dec. 11, 1990-Jan. 5, 1991 (Box 27, Folder 566)
    - Carol Ross/Riva Lehrer, Oct. 8-24, 1992 (Box 27, Folder 590A.)
    - A.I.R. Digital Portfolio -- Poster, 2006 (Box Shared Fales 116, Folder 2)
- Accretions 2007 - Series I: Administrative records
  - Subseries B: Gallery administration
    - Archive management - Phyllis Barr, 1997 (Box 28, Folder 979)
  - Subseries E: Programming
    - 25th Anniversary - Archive Committee, 1995-1997 (Box 28, Folder 980)
    - 25th Anniversary - Book Committee, 1995-1997 (Box 28, Folder 981)
    - 25th Anniversary - Correspondence re: traveling exhibition, 1995-1997 (Box 28, Folder 982)
    - 25th Anniversary - "Important messages and correspondence to follow up", 1995-1997 (Box 28, Folder 983)
    - 25th Anniversary - Publicity Committee, 1995-1997 (Box 28, Folder 984)
- Accretions 2007 - Series II: Individual artists
  NB: the dates attributed to these folders represent the range of dates of the materials in the folder, not the year of the artist's stint with the A.I.R. Gallery.
  - Kramer, Louise, 2007 (Box 28, Folder 985)
  - Riese, Beatrice, 2001-2004 (Box 28, Folder 986)
- Accretions 2007 - Series IV: Photos/slides
  - Subseries U: Misc. photos/slides
    - Artist/Event: 40 Wooster St. (inc. building facade, misc. exhibition openings, member portraits, interior of gallery, field trip photos) (Box 28, Folder 987, Box Shared Fales 116, Folder 1, Box Shared Fales 117, Flat-file-folder 4 Right)
      Contents: 78 photos (inc. duplicates), 11 slides, 1 negative, misc. paper files
      Photo credit: David Plakke/Art INK; L.L. Balmuth; J.N. Gifford
    - Artist/Event: Misc. slides (Sarah Grimm, unknown artist) (Box 21, Folder 988)
      Contents: 15 slides
- Accretions 2008 - Series I: Administrative Records
  Access Restrictions
  This series consists of born-digital materials,which may be unavailable to researchers.
  - Subseries B: Gallery Administration
    - Annual Reports, 2004-2006 (Box 28, Folder 989)
    - Fellowship Program, 2005-2006 (Box 28, Folder 989)
  - Subseries E: Programming
    - Announcement Cards, 2005-2008 (Box 28, Folder 989)
  - Subseries G: Press/Writings
    - Press Releases, 2005-2006 (Box 28, Folder 989)
- Accretions 2008 - Series III: Exhibition Files
  This series consists of born-digital materials, which may be unavailable to researchers.
  - Subseries A: Exhibitions held at A.I.R.
    - Generation 5, 2006-2008 (Box 28, Folder 989)
    - Postcard Show 2006 (Box 28, Folder 989)
    - Price Lists, 2005-2006 (Box 28, Folder 989)
  - Subseries B: Exhibitions held elsewhere
    - Hungary Portfolio, 2006 (Box 28, Folder 989)